<TitlePage>
  <Title>&aaa;</Title>
  <Version>Version &VERSION;</Version>

  <Author>Collin Bleak</Author>
  <Author>Fernando Flores Brito</Author>
  <Author>Feyishayo Olukoya</Author>

  <Copyright>&copyright; &COPYRIGHTYEARS; by Collin Bleak, Fernando Flores
    Brito, and Feyishayo Olukoya.<P/>

    &aaa; is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the
    terms of the <URL Text = "GNU General Public License">
    http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl.html</URL> as published by the Free Software
    Foundation; either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later
    version.
  </Copyright>

  <Abstract>
    The &aaa; package is a &GAP; package containing methods for transducers that
    can be represented as asynchronous automata. It builds on the ideas
    presented by Grigorchuk, Nekrashevich, and Sushanskii <Cite Key="GNS"/>, and
    then goes deeper to explore automorphisms via dynamics for the Higman groups
    as exposed by Bleak, Cameron, Maissel, Navas, and Olukoya
    <Cite Key="BCMNO"/>.
    <P/>
  </Abstract>

  <Acknowledgements>
    I would like to thank J. D. Mitchell for his help. His guidance vitally
    contributed to making this package have a coherent structure. &aaa; owes
    much of its structure to the &Semigroups; <Cite Key="SEMIGPS"/> package.<P/>

    Special thanks to Michael Torpey and Wilf Wilson for their continuous
    support. Their ample knowledge about &GAP; and programming has made the
    development of this package run smoothly.<P/>

    Thank you to Feyishayo Olukoya for his thoughts and help. His vast
    experience in the subject positively contributed to the efficiency of some
    functions.<P/>

    Manuel Delgado and Attila Egri-Nagy contributed to the function
    <Ref Func = "Splash"/>. The function <Ref Oper="DotTransducer"/>, written by
    Michael Torpey, is based on the &Digraphs; <Cite Key="DGPHS"/> package
    function they wrote called DotString.<P/>

    I would also like to acknowledge the valiant first attempt that Plamena
    Mineva-Sholz, Angela Richardson, and Ieva Vasiljeva made in the direction of
    writing a &GAP; package similar to this one. The name of this package was
    chosen to honour their good effort.<P/>
  </Acknowledgements>

</TitlePage>
